Guide to the World War I Posters File [1914]-1920 PR 55-7
New-York Historical Society
- Series VII: Miscellaneous, 7
  - Subseries VII.1: Miscellaneous, 33
    - Sky fighters of France / A French official exhibition of / Aerial battle paintings / By Lieut Henri Farre / Anderson Galleries / Park Ave and 59th St, 1917 (Folder 47)
      Portrait of aviator Capt. Guynemer
    - Yankee trophies / Captured from the German's / Pershing's vetrans / on the / War exhibit train / Georgetown, Thurs, Oct 17th (Folder 47)
    - Pour la liberte / Fete de L'Independence / 1776 4 Julliet 1918 (Folder 47)
      US Soldier, George Washington, US flag and ship; Statue of Liberty casting light
    - unspecified (Folder 47)
      2 Heads of females, draped in British, French Flags
    - Under four flags / Third / United State Official War Picture (Folder 47)
      4 soldiers of 4 nations
    - Les Ombres / Heros Belges / No. 2, 1914 (Folder 47)
      Silhouette of soldiers, dogs pulling arms
    - Bekanntmachung / Das / Verhalten der Bevoelkerung / Der Oberburgermeister / Aden auer /Coln, den 13 Dezember 1918 (Folder 47)
    - Hero land / The Greatest spectacle / The world has ever seen / For the greatest need / the world has ever known / Grand Central Palace, 1917 (Folder 47)
      British tank "Brittania" in action
    - Hero land / Or over the top with Uncle Sam and his allies / Grand Central Palace / Opening Nove 24th / A Bazaar with scenes / From the fighting fronts (Folder 47)
      French "Marianne" dressed as Roman warrior, holding shield of French Republic
    - Welcome 77th / Argonne Conquerors (Folder 47)
      Huge figure of the "Spirit of Argonne" hovering over soldiers in the field
    - 1492 Oct. 12 1918 / Liberty Day (Folder 47)
      Columbus pointing to Statue of Liberty
    - 1914! / Le Bon Aporte / No 4 (Folder 47)
      Hun looming over destroyed town
    - 1914! / Bravoure Allemande / No 2 (Folder 47)
      Dead boy; Hun with bayonet
    - 1914! / Les Assassins! / No 1 (Folder 47)
      2 marauding Huns with bloody knives
    - 1914! / Les "Tauben" Sur Paris" / No 5 (Folder 47)
      Hun smoking and drinking; Frenchman saluting
    - 1914! / Le Bataillon Sacre / No 3 (Folder 47)
      Soldiers at arms; flags rear
    - Have your answers / Ready / Census / State Military June 11 to 16 (Folder 47)
      Uncle Sam; census book; holidng quill to record responses
    - Les Ombres / Vers l'Abime / No 1, 1914 (Folder 47)
      Silhouette of derected soldier loading scrawney horse
    - Hero land / Grand / Central / Palace / Nov 24th / to Dec 12th (Folder 47)
  - Subseries VII.2: British and Foreign Recruitment, 34
    - Another call / "More / Men / And still / More / Until the enemy / is crushed" / Lord Kitchener (Folder 48)
      Soldier with bugle
    - Are you in this? (Folder 48)
      Military men, civilians, nurse, child, united in war effort, 1 civilian looking on
    - For food production / Forage & timber / The help of British women / Is urgent and indispensable / Women's Land Army / Enrol today (Folder 48)
    - The Empire's Need / Men / Munitions / Money / Which are you supplying?! (Folder 48)
      British Flag
    - If you were a German / Age 18 50 / You would be fighting / For the Kaiser / What are you doing / For the King? (Folder 48)
    - Your King and country / Need you / A wee "scrap o' paper" is Britains bond / To maintain the honour and glory / of the / British Empire, 1914 (Folder 48)
      soldier in kilt with bayonet
    - If the / Cap fits / You / Join / The Army / Today (Folder 48)
      Army Cap
    - For food production / Forage & timber / Recruits required / Immediately for the Women's Land Army (Folder 48)
      Woman with cow and milking pail
    - The key to the / Munitions / Men / and / Money / Are you / Helping / to Turn it? / Situation (Folder 48)
      key
    - To my people / George R.H. / Buckingham Palace (Folder 48)
    - Comparisons / In civil life / In H.M. forces, 1919 (Folder 48)
      Civilians, soldiers and comparison list of benefits
    - The Army of Today's / All Right (Folder 48)
      Head of soldier smoking pipe
    - Think! / Are you content for / Him to fight for you? / Won't you do your bit? / We shall win / But you must help / Join Today (Folder 48)
      Soldier with bayonet (black and white)
    - He did his duty / Will you do yours? (Folder 49)
      Portrait of deceased soldier, frame draped in bunting, medals, helmet and sword in front
    - Men of London / Each recruit / Means / Quicker peace / Join today / God save the King (Folder 49)
      houses of Parliament
    - Take up the / Sword of justice, 1915 (Folder 49)
      Brittania with sword, battleship, dead chldren in open seas
    - British subjects / It is your duty / to / Enlist / in the / British or Canadian Army / Headquarters British Recruiting Mission, 280 Broadway, NY (Folder 49)
    - To the Women / of Liverpool / Come to the recruiting rally at / St. George's Hall / WRAF (Folder 49)
    - Men of the Empire! / Rally round the flag / and / Jon the Army today / Your country needs you / Complete the second half million (Folder 49)
      Shield printed "Pro patria" before Allied flags
    - W.A.A.C. / Evey fit woman / Can release a fit man / Join the / Women's Army / Auxiliary Corps (Folder 49)
      WAAC women and Union Jack
    - Women's Royal Air Force / Recruiting Rally / St. Albans Market Place, Thursday, 10th October 1918 (Folder 49)
    - Queen Mary's Army Auxilary Corps / Kingston and District / Local Recruting Committee / Recruting Office, 60 Eden Street (Folder 49)
    - Be a sportsman / and lend a hand / to the lads at / the front / They want / Your help! (Folder 49)
    - "Be Honest with / Yourself. Be certain / That your socalled / Reason is not a / Selfish excuse." / Lord Ritchener / Enlist today (Folder 49)
      Soldiers silhouetted against battlefield
    - 17th november 1914 / 100,000 men / Are needed at once / to add to the ranks at the new armies / Join for the war (Folder 49)
    - Follow me! / Your country needs you (Folder 49)
    - Join the / R.A.M.C. / And learn a useful occupation which may help / You later in civilian life (Folder 49)
      Medical corpsman, signs listing skills: pharmacists, lab attendants, X-ray attendants, nursing orderlies, mental attendants, masseurs, hospital cooks, etc.
    - "A happy new year / To our gallant soldiers" / You can / Make it certain / I f you / Join Now, 1915 (Folder 49)
      soldiers marching, rays of sun spelling Victory rear, + 1915
    - National service / Women clerks / Wanted at once / For / Service / In France / With the British Army (Folder 49)
      Women Colunteers before ship leaving for France
    - Single men / Hundreds of thousands of / Married men have left their homes to fight for / King and counrty / Show your appreciation / By following their noble example (Folder 49)
      Mother and children at home, men fighting on battlefield
    - Which? / Have you a / Reason / Or only an / Excuse / For not enlisting / Now? (Folder 49)
    - Britons! / Your / Country / Needs / You (Folder 49)
      Message printed over grisaille maps of Great Britain
    - If you / Cannot / Join the Army / Try and / Get a / Recruit (Folder 49)
    - The late / Lord Robert's /Stirring words / To London's Special Service Battalion / Can you read this unmoved? (Folder 49)
    - Queen Mary's Army / Auziliary Corps / The girl / Behind the man / Behind the gun (Folder 49)
      Women in Army Auxiliary Corps uniform waving, other AAC women rear
    - To the women / of Canada / Won't you help / and send a man to / Enlist today? (Folder 49)
    - Take up the sword of justice / Join now, 1915 (Folder 49)
      Hand holding sword
    - To the women of Britain / Women are urgently / Wanted for employment. With the army at home /Enroll today in / Queen mary's / Army Auxillary Corps (Folder 49)
    - Britishers / Enlist today / 250 Broadway (Folder 49)
      Union Jack
    - In Polish: Poles / Under the Polish flag on to the fight / "For our liberty and for yours!" / Enlist today (Folder 49)
      Polish soldier carrying his country's flag; US and British flags rear
    - Queen Mary's Army Auxiliary Corps / 5,000 / Women / Clerks / Free / Training / If Required (Folder 49)
    - "What are / You doing / For the empire?" / Now's the time / to show what you / Can do! / Join the Army Today (Folder 49)
    - Free training / For clerkships / In / Queen Mary's / Army Auxilary Corps (Folder 49)
    - Queen Mary's Army Auxiliary Corps / The British Army calls urgently / For the help of British women / 7,000. Cooks and / Watiresses / Free training if required (Folder 49)
    - British Women! the / Royal Air Force / Needs your help / Enroll at once in the WRAF (Folder 49)
      WRAF Women pointing to enilstment sign, airplanes rear
    - Patriotic Service / for / British women / Women wanted urgently / WAAC / WRNS (Folder 49)
      Brittania with arms around 2 women, 1 in WRNS, 1 in WAAC
    - Britain's / Strong arm / And / Yours / Will carry us / Through / Enlist now (Folder 49)
    - The Royal Naval Canadian / Volunteer Reserve / Overseas Division (Folder 49)
    - More men / Are wanted for / His Majesty's Army / Enlist now (Folder 49)
    - Ministry of Labour / Women's War Services / A public / Recruiting / Meeting / Will be held on the / Bulwark, Brecon (Folder 49)
    - Free training for / Clerks, cooks, and waitresses / for / Queen Mary's / Army Auxiliary Corps (Folder 49)
    - Ministry of labour / Women's war services / Exhibition / Septermber 18 to September 25, 1918 (Folder 49)
    - Rally round the flag / We must have more men (Folder 49)
      Soldier, British flag on battlefield
    - Forward! / Forward to victory / Enlist now (Folder 49)
      Soldier charging on horseback
    - 1805 "England Expects" 1915 / Ary you doing your duty today? (Folder 49)
      Revolutionary war soldier against fleet of 1915 battleships
    - Queen Mary's / Army auxiliary Corps / We're looking / to you / to join our circle (Folder 50)
      WAAC member pointing to you; others smiling in rear
    - Wanted immediately for the / Royal Navy / Royal Marines (Folder 50)
    - Soldiers' seperation / Allowances / Increased rates from March 1, 1915 / Wives and children of married men / Motherless children / Other dependents of unmarried soldiers and widowers (Folder 50)
    - To the women / of Britain / Some of your men / Fold are holding back / On your account /Won't you prove your / Love for your country / By persuading / Them to go ? (Folder 50)
    - Your Country / Wants / You / and / 500,000 / More men / Like you / Don't wait! / But join now (Folder 50)
    - There are three / Types of men / Those who hear / the call and obey / those who delay / and others / to which do you belong? (Folder 50)
    - Why aren't / You / In khaki? / You'll be wanted / Enlist at once (Folder 50)
    - Wireless operators / Urgently wanted / Write or call / The Traffice Manager / Marconi International Marine Communication Co LTD / marconi House, Strand WC 2 (Folder 50)
      Young man in marine uniform before room with man with wireless at his desk
    - France's Day / In aid of the / French Red Cross / (British Committee) / Carlsisle and District / Sat Oct 12 / Come and help, 1917 (Folder 50)
      Nurses attending wounded soldiers
    - England expects / and / England must not and / Will not be disappointed / Recruits wanted / For the / Royal Naval Division (Folder 50)
      Ship at sea with flags flying
    - It's going to be a long / Drawnout sturggle / The Prime Minister / At the Guildhall / Novmeber 9th 1914 (Folder 50)
    - Remember! / "England expects" / Are you between 15 and 40 /j If so the navy requires / You for its glorious service / Join today (Folder 50)
      Sailor silhouetted against naval canons
  - Subseries VII.3: Foreign Non-recruitment, 35
    - Play the game / To all ranks of British forces / It is our duty to respect the / Property of our allies.. .. .. (Folder 51)
    - Britain's Day / December 7, 1917 / America / This day / Pays tribute to / Britain's / Achievements in / the Great War, 1918 (Folder 51)
      Busts of PH; George Washington before Sulgrave Manor, home of Washington's forfathers in England
    - Hoot Mon / The Kilties are here! / British Recruting Week / July 16 21 (Folder 51)
      Uncle Sam, John Bull, and Scotsman in kilt playing bagpipe
    - Side by side / Britannia / Britain's Day Dec 7th, 1918 (Folder 51)
      Uncle Same, Britannia arm in arm
    - America's tribute to Britain (Folder 51)
      Ameican eagle, British lion - woodcut
    - Back him up! / Buy Victory Bonds (Folder 52)
      Back of Soldier with bayonet nearing battlefield
    - Fight or pay / That others may fight / British freedom / or / Prussian militarism / Which? / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - How can you cheer / For the boys / When they / Come home / If you have neither / Fought nor paid / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - If you can't fight / You can pay / Subscribe to the Canadian Patiriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - Did you do anything / To / Beat Germany / Last year? / Fight or pay (Folder 52)
      British and Canadian flags
    - Have you asked / Yourself / 1. Is British freedom worh defending? / 2. Am I helping de / Fend it? / 3. If not, why not? (Folder 52)
      Hand with finger pointing, Union Jack
    - "Dad's on the line / Busy fighting" / What are / You doing? / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - Carlisle / Hut day / Church Army Recreation / Huts and tents / Urgently needed / On all fronts, 1917 (Folder 52)
      Soldiers filing into Church Army Hut
    - To naval men / L1 for 15'6 /War Savings / Certificates / Buy instalments (Folder 52)
    - To maintain the prosperity / of Canada / Buy / Victory Bonds / 5 interest tax free (Folder 52)
      3 pictures of prosperity: a farm, factory, shipbuilding yard
    - King George's Fund / For sailors / Patron: his Majesty the King (Folder 52)
      Brittanial withwsowrd and shield / hand with torch of liberty emerging from wather with boats at sea
    - Do your bit / Save food (Folder 52)
      Sailor in British navy; ships at sea
    - It's worth while! / That's why / Buy War Savings Certificates, 1917 (Folder 52)
      2 workmen having lunch, discussing purchase of savings certificates
    - Coal / The coal you are / Going without is / Forging the key for vicotry (Folder 52)
      Coal shuttle
    - If you cannot / Give a life / You can / Save a life / By helping the Canadian Red Cross (Folder 52)
    - Our boys must face the / Ravages of war / They need not face the / Ravages of disease / Help .. .. By / Subscribing to Canadian Red Cross (Folder 52)
    - Back them up / My duty / Invest in the / War loan (Folder 52)
      man with hand in pocket to get money; soldiers rear
    - Will your subscription / Mean to your family / A sacrifice / Equal to that of the soldier's families? / does our /Common cause / Not demand as much / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - Victory / Bonds / Will help stop / This / Kultur vs. Humanity (Folder 52)
      Canadian soldier with dad Red Cross nurse in Waxer; U boat rear; life saver with Llandovery Castle printed on it
    - Are you one of those / .. .. Neither / Fighting nor paying / Fight or pay / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - Can I afford / to pay for freedom / Belgium must afford / To pay for slavery / Canadians / .. .. Must provide.. .. / Saving us from Belgium's fate / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - Doing my bit / Four years / Do yours / Buy / Victory Bonds (Folder 52)
      Soldier in kilt, holding up four fingers
    - Buy / National / War Bonds /Regularly / Week by Week (Folder 52)
      Brittania
    - They serve France / How can I serve Canada? / Buy Victory / Bonds (Folder 52)
    - Help our district / Win this flag / Honor Flag / Victory / Loan / 1918 / Awarded by / His Excellence the Governor of Canada to Districts exceeding their quota (Folder 52)
      Honor flag
    - Some women / Are sending their men / Some men / Are giving their lives / What are you doing? / Fight or pay / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - England expects / Buy National War Bonds / or / War Savings Certificates / Now (Folder 52)
      Decorated British sailor, ships rear
    - Write a cheque / Today / For / National War Bonds (Folder 52)
      Inkwell with pen
    - Yours / Not to do and die / Yours but to go and / Buy / Victory Bonds / 1918 (Folder 52)
      Soldiers with bayonets
    - Jutland Day / Thursday, May 31st / In aid of / the John Cornwell v.c. Ntional Memorial / Cottage Homes / For / Disabled Soldiers (Folder 52)
      Ships at sea; medal marked John Cornwell v.c.
    - Pave the way / To victory / Buy / Victory Bonds (Folder 52)
      Soldiers on armored cars waving
    - How much / Should I give? / For $16 a month / You can keep a man at the front / Subscribe now to the Canadian Patriotic Fund (Folder 52)
    - "If ye break faith / Ye shall not sleep" / Buy Victory Bonds (Folder 52)
      Soldier before grave in Flanders Field, filled with poppies
    - Faith in Canada / Use it all for / Victory / Bonds (Folder 52)
      Soldiers on battlefield, chest of coins / jewelry
    - Thank God / And the / Sailors / For my / Good breakfast (Folder 52)
      Central cirlce of family at breakfast table; against background of shipbuilding yard
    - India Day /France / Flanders. Saldonica / Mesopotamia / Egypt / Palestine / East Africa (Folder 52)
      Multi racial soldiers on the battlefield
    - Are you saving / For the children? / Save for their education and give / Them a start in life / Buy / War Savings Certificates (Folder 52)
      Father, 2 children, War Savings Certificates
    - Crippled boys / Wounded soldiers / Princess Louise / Military wards / Heritage craft / Schools / Chailey / "Educate / Convalescence" / of / Wounded men, 1915 (Folder 52)
      6 photos of men at various craft activities
    - Ministry of Labour / Employment Department / Tooting local / Davisory Committee, 1918-10-21 (Folder 52)
    - Thank them with / War Bonds (Folder 52)
      Canon with ammo and bags of money
    - Your maxim / "Buy War Bonds" (Folder 52)
      Soldiers behind maching gun with 5% national war bonds as ammo
    - A Y.M.C.A. Welcome for the men of / HM Forces near the / London railway stations / "The Shakespeare" Hut / London's latest YMCA for soldiers (Folder 52)
      12 photos of YMCA huts in London
    - Yes / Complete Victory / If you eat / Less bread (Folder 52)
      Loaf of bread
    - Town topics / The / Suicide / Of / Germany, 1914-08-08 (Folder 53)
    - The Referee / The Unique Sunday Journal / France / Invades / Germany (Folder 53)
    - War! War! / Described and pictured by / Robert L. Dunn / (Collier's war correspondent) / How Russia lost / With / Motion pictures (Folder 53)
    - Jerusalem captured: The holy city wrested from the Turks (Folder 53)
      4 photographs of Jerusalem; 1 of Gen. Sir Edmund Allenby, Commander of British forces in Palestine
    - Lloyd's News Sunday, August 9 / Kaiser's nephew / Reported / Captured, 1914 (Folder 53)
    - Daily Telegraph / Sunday August 9 / War Edition / Fierce fighting / in Alsace / Liege holding / Out / British sieze / German colony, 1914 (Folder 53)
    - Sunday Times / French / Invade / Alsace, 1914-08-09 (Folder 53)
    - The Weekly Dispatch / Full list / of Amphion / Victims / [Official], 1914-08-09 (Folder 53)
    - John Bull Weekly / To Hell / With / Servia! (Folder 53)
    - Observer / Yesterday's / Great / Battle: / 45,000 / Losses (Folder 53)
    - The Sporting Times / Otherwise known as "The Pinic 'uh' / Us / And / At 'Em, 1914-08-08 (Folder 53)
    - Reynold's / Special Sunday Edition / French / Victory / in Alsace / Fierce Fighting, 1914-08-09 (Folder 53)
    - The Weekly Dispach / 3 German / Army / Corps / Put Out of Action, 1914-08-09 (Folder 53)
    - Times / Battle / In / Alsace / Special Cables, 1914-08-09 (Folder 53)
    - Reynold's / Special Sunday Edition / German / Army's / Critical / Position, 1914-08-09 (Folder 53)
    - Reynold's / Late Night War Edition / German / Army in / Flight / Official (Folder 53)
    - The / World / War / By J.L. Garvin (Folder 53)
    - The People / Special Edition / Germans / On the Run! / French Victory / in Alsace / Amphion / Furhter Survivors, 1914-08-09 (Folder 53)